hello this is Eric with a few notes on
today's release this was recorded over
half a year ago and I've sat on it
because I didn't want to release it I
had hoped that the story it discusses
would have been followed up by others as
I never wanted to be entangled with it
instead that story has barely moved for
some reason there is no one capable
within the world of institutional media
or government of moving this enormous
story forward despite worldwide interest
I've elsewhere named that unseen force
the disc or distributed ideas
suppression complex what I see when
watching this video of the episode in
question is a frightened 53 year old man
in an unscripted and perhaps
occasionally rambling hour of discussion
of Jeffrey Epstein he doesn't exactly
know how to say what he has got to get
across but perhaps that is because he
isn't simply a middle-aged man at all
when I look closer I see a terrified 10
or 11 year old boy who many years ago
was sent to a therapist why was that
child so terrified of going to see a
therapist you may ask well because of
inappropriate events set in motion by
the therapist behavior at the first of
their two meetings that however was not
what caused the lasting terror
despite the therapist being a trained
and established authority figure and the
boy being a minor it was possible for
the boy to simply and firmly say no I do
not want that you must stop thus the boy
is not a survivor he was not a victim
and he did not want a random broken
person to be integrated into his life
story today the man in that chair
addressing the camera is simply the man
that became of an unlucky boy who was
sent to see a professionally licensed
therapist who crossed his path what was
terrifying instead was that when I
explained that I did not ever wish to go
back to that person office I was forced
against my will and with a good amount
of screaming in terror I might add to go
again for a second meeting at that
second meeting I was intimidated by the
failed and inappropriate therapist who
was obviously himself terrified being
forced back into such a dark office
alone as a boy to be berated threatened
and shamed by an out-of-control
representative of the world of
institutional Authority alerted me to
just how badly outgunned the individual
is when confronted by the terrifying
reality of institutional actors
attempting to silence a lone voice why
would no one listen to the boy when he
told them what had happened why wouldn't
any one adult powerful and credentialed
speak up
that child and his right to be free of
the supposed therapy and therapists
could no one see the terror in the
child's eyes why simply because two
sessions had been booked did he need to
continue with this random therapist was
clearly a damaged soul and one who
needed real therapy much more than the
boy this episode is ultimately about the
world of institutions the institutions
of journalism that will regularly
destroy individuals by reputation
but who will generally not ask
comparable questions of other
institutions the institutions of the
intelligence world which OS information
as to what is known about Jeffrey
Epstein ghilane Maxwell and their
operation the institutions of government
that will not hold hearings into out of
control intelligence activities as we
did in the 1970s and the institutions of
Technology which track our every move
and know all our secrets yet cannot
locate a single individual like Jeffrey
Epstein's accomplice who completely and
probably seems to have vanished from the
face of the earth as of March 2020 but
just as this episode is about
institutions it is also about
individuals and the various ways that
they are made vulnerable to
institutional objectives because every
individual may be destroyed at will by
the same complex of institutions that
are themselves deciding not to act with
vigor and policing each other we are all
at risk when we deviate from their
scripts and expect structural change
thus the act of pointing out the
absurdity of the story is in fact
terrifying which gets to the questions
raised by the young boy in our story why
will no one listen to me when I say I do
not ever wish to encounter the monster
or the official class he represents ever
again why must I go back to the same
institutions that harm me why does a
child evident terror mean nothing to any
adult nor any institution at all why can
we not talk openly about the risks to
the individuals from the expert in
authority classes when we have a
conflict between them as it happens
analogs of all of those personal
questions are now being asked in hushed
tones about Jeffrey Epstein and the
bizarre institutional response to his
story why are we not expending resources
to figure out what giant structure we
apparently just tripped over are we
really going to sit here and not ask
whether this was a protected or
state-sponsored pedophile running some
kind of intelligence operation to
control people in positions of power
wealth and influence are we okay with
the idea that we aren't even asking on
the record questions about whether
Arendt
hodgins communities traffic and underage
minors some as young as 12 years of age
well I have an answer for that boy one
day you will become a man and you will
fear loss in the battle between the
flawed and vulnerable individual that
all adults eventually become in the
amoral institutional world who continues
to hold most of the best cards you will
learn the story of Jean Seberg and that
alone will change your life you will not
know to whom you can turn you will come
to believe that there is no news media
nor just the system nor social movement
nor representative government that truly
cares about protecting minors in real
terms when institutional power money
secrecy and sex are all woven together
you will become part of the problem by
remaining silent for a while to cope
with your fears that is unless you are
able to overcome them to clear your
throat and finally say you know what I
refuse to continue to be part of the
charade in this way anymore I have
always felt Jeffrey Epstein was a
construct and I now feared that he was a
state-sponsored pedophile protected by
governments and I have kept quiet too
long partially out of fear that the
trail could lead to either or both of
the two nations I loved most in this
world
I'm not really here for myself and I've
been avoiding this and perhaps at least
directly I'm not even mostly here for
the victims of Jeffrey Epstein and his
organization I am at last really here
selfishly for a young boy long gone why
abandoned to prove to him there was
actually possible at personal risk to
stand up for children and against the
system these young girls are no less
deserving of course but I don't know any
of them personally so I will stick to
the issue that animates me the
individual standing against the
institution's who would crush him or her
so too that long dead and previously
abandoned form herself let me just say
this sorry I'm a little late kid I
became afraid that the imperfections of
what I'm about to say next could
deranged my adult life and make me
vulnerable to those who will destroy
anything and anyone who threatens them
using everything at their disposal
I apologize for my cowardice it is one
of many character flaws that I am
working to correct but you as a boy did
nothing wrong and it will be a pleasure
to stand up for you come with me you're
a solid kid who didn't deserve this and
I think you deserve a better champion
but Jesus wasn't available so you got me
instead let's do this thing I know this
is crazy but I think that there's even a
remote chance we can take these guys we
can't at least try and go down swinging
just release it flaws and all and hope
that the world is more kind than it's
failing institutions but that said stay
tuned please be a little bit forgiving
and enjoy the episode hello you found
the portal I think this is going to be a
little bit of an unusual episode because
it's going to deal with a current event
and I try to make most of these episodes
somewhat more timeless so that they're
not referenced to something in specific
that is going to age but the event that
I'm talking about is the very mysterious
circumstances that are currently
animating so many people's speculations
in the news that is the apparent death
of Jeffrey Epstein by his own hand now I
want to say first of all that I have
absolutely no special inside knowledge
of the situation
I know people who knew him and I met him
once but it is not like I have any
particular line on information from any
particularly interesting source about
the situation furthermore I don't think
that I'm going to be using any special
kind of analysis that is known only to
me but I did want to talk to people
about responsible conspiracy theorizing
that is in the minds of many people
believe that conspiracy theorists are
people like Alex Jones people who are
spouting all sorts of crazy ideas some
of which might have some grain of truth
in them but in general it feels like an
exercise in talking to the tinfoil hat
crowd now I don't know much about Alex
Jones perhaps he's better than I think
he is but what I want to talk about is a
different kind of conspiracy theorizing
so without further ado welcome to this
episode of the portal on the subject of
Jeffrey Epstein so the first thing I
want to do is I want to be relatively
clear that I'm somebody who believes
that there is a fair amount of
organization behind the scenes usually
of a relatively low level of
organization that is unknown to the
people who are watching TV or listening
to let's say NPR on the radio and at
various times I've dug more deeply into
various stories and so I want you to
have some idea of my history in the
space
in the 1980s and 1990s I became very
active in believing that the so-called
stem shortage of scientists and
engineers that was claimed by the policy
research and analysis division of the
National Science Foundation was in fact
a conspiracy in order to make life
easier for employers who would be facing
American scientists with an ability to
bargain and make higher wage demands and
that the National Academy of Sciences
the National Science Foundation
interceded interceded on the behalf of
employers which was tampering in the
labor market in an absolutely vital
sector resulting in the Immigration Act
of 1990 or enacted 90 as it was called
at that point I also became aware of
what I have termed the bore Haas
rectangle theory that is that employers
generally in free market economies when
they are complaining about labor
shortages are actually trying to
transfer wealth from labor to capital
complaining instead that there is a
small inefficiency that needs to be
rectified which we might call the
harberger triangle so that is employers
claim that there's a small inefficiency
but in fact you're seeking large
transfer payments from the vulnerable to
the well-heeled I also believe that
NAFTA and the free trade agreement from
the 1990s was the kind of conspiracy
supported by the economics establishment
of the United States that they knew that
in fact economics was not a sorry trade
free trade was not a freebie it was not
in fact a rising tide that lifted all
boats but was in fact again a transfer
which was claimed to be a pure good for
everyone this is the difference between
something called the Kaldor Hicks
objective function and the Pareto
objective function I also believe that
string theory was largely a desperation
measure in physics that was sold to the
world to buy time when in fact the field
of theoretical physics was failing
I also claimed that the Boskin
Commission formed by packwood and
Moynihan in the mid-1990s
was a kind of conspiracy to transfer
actually a trillion dollars by using the
fact that Social Security payments are
indexed to inflation as well as tax
brackets being indexed to inflation so
that if you could show that the CPI was
overstated and you could reduce the CPI
you could transfer millions without
having to touch the so-called third rail
of American politics this brings us to
the two trading fortunes in New York
City that during the first decade of the
new millennium made no sense to me and
those were Bernie Madoff then referred
to as the Jewish tea bill and Jeffrey
Epstein in the case of Madoff I made a
wrong guess I believe that Bernie Madoff
was front-running a traditional business
that he held using actual orders that he
knew were being placed and in his hedge
fund was effectively cheating based on
the inside information he had from a
legitimate business in an illegitimate
business I goofed and it was wrong in
fact he was operating a pyramid scheme
it didn't occur to me in the case of
Jeffrey Epstein we'll get to that
shortly but it made no sense when I
actually looked into the story let me
keep going I also became aware of what I
called the gated institutional narrative
in effect a storyline or narrative that
many institutions claim to believe but
would easily be disrupted if Outsiders
were allowed to comment on it and a way
of walling it off so that these
narratives could in fact govern the
American mindset and get us talking
about things that we would never
normally choose to talk about in terms
that seem completely unnatural to me
this is also the origin of the four
quadrant theory which I've pushed out
which is a way of intimidating people
away from holding positions that are not
supposed to be habitable like for
example if you're a Xena philic
restriction astana Gration supposedly
this is the position the most famous
example of the theory is Kathy Newman
questioning Jordan Peterson saying so
what you're really saying is and this is
an implied threat which is the
try to express something subtle you will
be mapped to expressing something that
is beyond the pale in addition in the
early 2000s I came out talking against
the Great Moderation and mortgage-backed
securities I published in I think I
submitted in 2001 to risk magazine my
first article on mortgage-backed
securities and I kept talking about the
fact that we had not actually but
banished volatility from the markets and
this is a period of time where I was
sort of going around the hedge fund
conference circus with a Nassim Taleb
talking about the fact that even though
volatility was decreasing that this was
not a permanent state of affairs
furthermore I objected to non-recourse
loans in the wake of the great financial
crisis and I've talked openly about the
false narratives of the inevitability of
Hillary Clinton versus Bernie Madoff
which was a giant mistake in my opinion
of the New York Times interceding in an
election in a completely inappropriate
way when they doubled down and came up
with the impossibility of Donald Trump
which I tried to use preference
falsification the theory of Tim or Quran
we just had on the program in order to
say that the likelihood of a Trump
victory was far higher than anyone had
imagined I had also said various things
about brexit where I thought that the
likelihood that that would actually pass
was high and afterwards after the 2016
election I talked about fake news as an
invented concept it had been discussed
before that but there was a slew of
articles about fake news which I still
think was a completely inauthentic
attempt to put in a placeholder for some
ability to control the Internet in
particular the large platforms so that a
repeat of 2016 could never happen in the
year 2020 in effect that there should be
some way of restoring the gated
institutional narrative which had
clearly broken I've also been quite
vocal on the data and society
alternative influencer Network theory on
particularly on the Dave Rubin program I
think that this was a transparent
attempt to attempt to control the
Internet in the
ability to uh influencers to gain
stature if they're outside the gated
institutional network and I also made
several tweets around Jeffrey Epstein
one of them which says that if he has in
fact a construct of the intelligence
community either the US intelligence
community or a foreign one then clearly
he could not be allowed to live many
people also made similar predictions but
that gives you an idea of the kind of
thing that I've been talking about I in
general believe that where we are as a
society is that we are expected to
believe in narratives that any person
with a modicum of intelligence and a
certain awareness of history cannot
possibly be expected to believe with the
straight face all right that leads us to
the doorstep of what I call responsible
conspiracy theorizing now in order to do
responsible conspiracy theorizing it's
important not to be definite about
things we don't know and I'm gonna try
to let you know that I actually don't
know what has happened in fact the
official story is quite possible from
what I know it's not impossible the
Jeffrey Epstein was a perverted very
rich man who is dead by his own hand in
custody through an unlikely but not
impossible set of circumstances however
unfortunately for me I met Jeffrey
Epstein in 2004 I think or perhaps 2003
and I met him in his home in Manhattan
on 71st Street when he took an interest
in talking to me both as a scientist
into somebody who was interested in
foreign exchange trading I found that
meeting so bizarre and so remarkable
that it is stuck with me ever since
recently when the news turned to Jeffrey
Epstein my wife said to me you know Eric
you called this when you met him early
on and I said what do you remember and
she said that you called me immediately
afterwards and you said I've just met a
construct
and she asked what it was a construct
and I said I met somebody who appears to
be a hedge-fund billionaire who I don't
think is actually in fact involved
particularly in hedge fund trading I
felt like what I was meeting was an
actor an actor who had been hired or
constructed to play a part
ever since that meeting I've used one
word and one word alone when talking
about Jeffrey Epstein and particularly
with people who knew him who were
friends or acquaintances or colleagues
of mine and by using the word construct
repeatedly I attempted to make an
indelible image that I was very bothered
and was in fact making a prediction that
one day it was quite probable although
not definite and certainly not certain
the Jeffrey Epstein would be revealed to
be something other than what he had
apparently been chronicled as being and
what he had portrayed himself as being
as a result I now have a different
situation because I was making this
prediction early on and I had no idea
what turn of events would bring us to
the present I was quite vocal about
something which perhaps today if I knew
how things were going to end up I would
have said nothing at all so I feel in
fact a little bit more vulnerable having
spoken out on this as if I know
something rather than just a person who
found himself in remarkable
circumstances and didn't believe what he
was being told and this is why I'm doing
this right now in part I wanted to
scourge everything that I know or
believed that I know about Jeffrey
Epstein so that it will be very clear to
anybody who would attempt to intimidate
me that there is nothing to be gained I
know nothing proprietary I have no
special insight information and I want
to get to how I came to believe that
Jeffrey as Epstein was quite likely the
construct of an intelligence community
either ours in the US or somewhere else
so in order to do responsible conspiracy
theorizing my first rule is is that one
should not attempt to allege a type of
conspiracy that has never been
encountered before over the years many
conspiracies have been uncovered and so
we have a menu if you will of proven
conspiracies with which we can try to
figure out whether something is in fact
possible and to give you an idea I'm
gonna list a small number of
conspiracies that have been proven and
give you the idea of why these things
figure in my imagination and I think
that what will happen over time is that
you'll see that I'll refer to the same
conspiracies over and over again because
they give us an idea of the boundaries
of the possible first of all one
question is it possible that mainstream
media can be weaponized by the
intelligence community for the purpose
of destroying a well-known individual
that is as I am recording this I am
aware that the intelligence community
could decide to tarnish or destroy or in
their words cheapen my reputation by
planting stories in mainstream media in
this case I would point people to one of
the most important examples we have
which is the destruction of Jean Seberg
the leading actress who was originally
found by Otto Preminger to play Joan of
Arc and also used by jean-luc Godard in
the film breathless as the heroine Jean
Seberg was accused due to her radical
politics active in the Black Panther
Party of cuckolding her husband and
bearing the child of a black panther and
in a news item that was planted by the
FBI with Joyce Haber of the Los Angeles
Times later repeated by Newsweek the
great thing about this is you don't have
to believe me you can just look it up
does the u.s. have the ability to
assassinate its own people who may be
trying to do good well in the case of
the person who invented the term the
rainbow coalition this appears to be the
case it wasn't Jesse Jackson it was in
fact a man named Fred Hampton and my
understanding is he was trying to get
black
street gangs to stop warring with each
other to form a political coalition and
was assassinated for his attempt to do
so in his bed in Chicago Illinois so
this shows that assassinations by our
intelligence community in our particular
form of secret police the FBI is also
possible can you have a highly
coordinated silent hit with tremendous
complexity going off almost without a
hitch I believe that the surveillance
photos that we have seen in Dubai
indicate that this is in fact has
occurred recently I'm not going to say
who carried out the hit because that is
not known but it is widely believed to
be a particular country that is not hard
to guess is it possible to suicide
someone normally we think of committing
suicide as an individual action but do
we ever find the intelligence
communities attempting to in the sense
of a transitive verb suicide someone by
letting them know that they will turn
their life into a living hell so that
committing suicide is the only way out
in fact this is a what the subject of
the FB i--'s letter by the hand of
Sullivan to Martin Luther King jr. was
when the attempt was to tell King that
he was finished and that if he didn't
commit suicide that his legacy and his
name would be tarnished would an
intelligence community ever contemplate
using organized crime such as the Cosa
Nostra in order to carry out an act that
it didn't want to do itself this is what
we found
the comedian Dick Gregory was considered
being subjected to when we found out
that the FBI was thinking about having
La Cosa Nostra be informed that he had
been talking about union activities and
labor racketeering so yes it is quite
possible that the intelligence community
would use organized crime this is also a
proven fact would we ever have the use
of orgies and honey pots together with
an elaborately constructed backstory in
which an actor and the character they
played were entirely different this is
in fact the story of Le Cohn perhaps
Israel's most famous spy discovered in
Damascus
as if he was an Arab who had come from
Argentina as a playboy using alcohol and
women in order to integrate himself into
the highest echelons of Syrian society
particularly the intelligence and
defense communities so yes people are
constructed to be something other than
they are and honey pots are very much
a possible use in the intelligence world
is their intelligence community interest
in control of the media I would commend
that you look at Project Mockingbird is
there any attempt to gain control of
innocent influencers that is are there
any circumstances in which people simply
have the crime of being influential used
against them in fact you can look for
section a of the reserve index
people to be rounded up in times of
national emergency inside the United
States
this might include professors labor
organizers professionals authors the
independently wealthy in other words
there is very much an interest in
keeping track of people who have done
nothing wrong but in times of national
emergency you might want to make sure
that none of these people are capable of
influencing the population lastly one of
the things that we hear most frequently
is is that there is no ability to have
conspiracies because any large group of
people would not be able to keep a
secret it's a really silly idea because
COINTELPRO which was discovered by the
Citizens Committee to investigate the
FBI in 1971 when the word showed up in
documents they stole from an office of
the FBI in media Pennsylvania and then
they used the Freedom of Information Act
in order to find out what COINTELPRO was
and it turned out that it was a
permanent dirty tricks campaign living
inside of the FBI and that the deep
throat construct inside of the Watergate
story of Woodward and Bernstein was in
fact mark felt who I believe was the
head of COINTELPRO after J Edgar Hoover
so what we're going to be doing is
simply exploring how the things that
have been proven to be true might enter
into the story of the unfortunate
Jeffrey Epstein in this circumstance I
want to say what it is that I'm making
for and I'm gonna be talking about the
church and pike commissions and having
them redone in the current era if you
don't know what the church and pike
committees were I believe the Church
Committee was in the Senate and the pike
committee was in the house they were an
attempt to invest our own investigate
our own intelligence community in order
to understand what the US had become in
an era that was rife with dirty tricks
campaigns often against our own citizens
and often against people who had done
nothing wrong other than exercising
their constitutional rights to dissent
from official narrative and in general
mainstream perspectives it is extremely
important to me that the United States
remain a place that is not only not
hostile to heterodox thinking but leads
the world in heterodox thinking this is
our comparative advantage against places
like China and Russia which use fear to
intimidate their people if we cannot
have heterodox thinkers operating with a
feeling of safety in our own country I
believe that we are lost because I don't
think we are going to be able to compete
with powers that are able to organize
people and use violence to coerce people
into doing things that our people would
find absolutely unpalatable further if
you're in running a kind of conspiracy
and I don't I'm not against conspiracies
that I'm not against the intelligence
community but it's important that the
conspiracies be ethical that they be
public minded and that they be of a very
high caliber you shouldn't be able to
trip over a conspiracy doing nothing
wrong and find yourself in a world of
pain what I'm going to say about Jeffrey
Epstein is that if the official story
isn't true and that in fact he was an
intelligence community construct either
a US or foreign then he was a very poor
intelligence construct it was easy to
trip over Jeffrey Epstein he was not
well construct
and I'll get into what I think may have
been going on shortly but the key point
is I had someone potentially reach out
to me and intimidate me a bit I don't
know if it was directed but they seem to
know a great deal about me and they were
trying to I thought dissuade me from
talking about this and investigating
this my feeling about this is as if I'm
tripping over your construct than you
goofed it's not my problem you drew up
this person whoever you may be if I'm
correct about this and you made a
mistake and I'm gonna say what that
mistake is but it shouldn't be my job to
get out of your way it should be your
job to make sure that I never run across
your problem so I believe that Jeffrey
Epstein if he was an intelligence
construct was extremely badly drawn
alright here's what went into my meeting
of Jeffrey Epstein my recollection is is
that Jeffrey Epstein had a staff of
young adult women who I would guess were
in their late 20s perhaps early 30s they
seemed very professional they seemed
very attractive and that they seemed to
take his schedule and all of the sort of
incidental executive function duties off
of his hands principally I dealt with
them according to my recollection and
not with Jeffery directly I believed I
became aware that Jeffrey wanted to see
me
and since I was at that time involved in
a small hedge fund I went to see him on
71st Street across from the frick museum
when I got to the door it was an
extraordinary experience he in fact was
living in what was from an Hatton which
is famous for relatively small dwellings
even for the very rich in a very large
townhouse I went through the door I was
greeted treated professionally and I was
led to a waiting room in that waiting
room which I believe was off to the left
as you entered I sat in the chair for a
while and I noticed that there was a
large mechanical piece of art and I
believed that it had some electronics to
it after a while sitting in my chair my
recollection is that I went up to this
art object and I started trying to
inspect
as I was looking at the art object which
I thought was quite innocent I suddenly
thought that I saw something like a
lipstick camera that is a very small
camera whose lens was staring straight
at me my first thought was holy cow I've
discovered that there's a hidden camera
that has been trained on me while I've
been in this room I thought myself to be
rather clever for having found it but my
second thought was exactly the reverse
of this
I bet this isn't that difficult to find
the object that it was buried in
attracts attention and it must be that
people who look at this object
invariably find the camera and then I
started asking myself am I supposed to
find the camera is this a test is this
person trying to make sure I'm
comfortable with being under
surveillance the whole thing was now
quite queer and I went back and I sat
down as I recall it shortly thereafter
almost responsive to finding the camera
my recollection is that I was called out
of this room and I was led to the back
where I was to wait for Jeffrey Epstein
in a very large room with an enormous
dining table now what was most memorable
about this dining table was that it had
a tablecloth that I thought to be
incredibly inappropriate what I recall
was is that it had the appearance of a
draped coffin because the tablecloth was
an extremely large American flag if I
recall correctly there was another
gentleman perhaps another hedge fund
person or a science person who sat to my
left and I stared at this tablecloth and
I thought oh you're gonna serve me food
on a tablecloth made out of the flag of
my country or perhaps you're going to
give me a beverage that might spill on
the American flag is this a test of some
kind of my loyalty to my country or
whether I have some sort of morality
that isn't burdened by some petty
reverence to an inanimate object I
couldn't tell what was going on but I
started getting extremely agitated and
in fact angry and I think my my feelings
that involved an expletive which is F
the person who decided that this was a
good idea to put it in America
table flags a tablecloth to test new
people coming to the house my
recollection is that Jeffrey entered
from the right with a young woman in my
mind I remember her as being perhaps 20
to 23 she was extremely attractive as I
recall Jeffery sat down and began
bouncing this woman on his knee so he
motioned for her to sit down and she
appeared to be quite happy in this role
as Jeffrey asked questions and discussed
science theories I had about markets how
they related to gauge Theory theoretical
physics I don't remember the man saying
much to me who is also in the room at
the time and so all I have a
recollection of is the four of us
Jeffrey the woman on his leg and the
other gentleman and myself my
recollection is also that in order to
test our will power and concentration
that Jeffrey would bounce this woman
occasionally that she would giggle in
order to test our resolve as to whether
we could stay focused in the
conversation I found him to be quite
intelligent he clearly was no slouch but
I also found that every single
interaction with him resulted in my
being back footed conversationally he
was constantly trying to throw me off
guard and at some level I was also
irritated and anger and I was trying to
keep my cool during this entire
interaction and I thought to myself I
don't know anybody who behaves this way
I knew several rich people at that point
in my life and I've known many more very
wealthy people perhaps billionaires
billionaires of ten and eleven figure
fortunes to the best of my recollection
I've never met a single other person who
behaved in such a strange way he didn't
appear to be really that focused on
markets and trading and he appeared
instead to be focused in creating a kind
of cartoonish notion of what a
billionaire might be in a very poorly
drawn James Bond or Marvel comic movie
and in so doing I came to start to
believe that I was not really talking to
somebody who was a hedge fund manager or
a fine
Cerre but that I was instead talking to
a very intelligent and extremely
charismatic man my recollection was that
he was magnetically handsome perhaps a
little off in certain ways certainly
he's been compared to Ralph Lauren which
was my thought but he was prematurely
gray if I recall the image and he had a
kind of charisma that could probably be
quantified in an era facial recognition
there was something very very unusual
and compelling about him despite the
fact that he was more than a little bit
lube richest the meeting ended abruptly
at some point and I walked out I
remember feeling that there are very few
times in your life when you feel the
hair on the back of your neck rise up I
don't know whether that's literally what
happened but it was certainly the sense
that I had met something unholy and I
remember calling my wife and I remember
talking to her and I've used the word
construct ever since now in order to do
responsible conspiracy theorizing there
are a couple of techniques that I would
like to share that I use one is that I
would like to distinguish two separate
elements that may in fact be the same
thing let's imagine that the character
that I met is in fact the forward facing
construct and that there was an
underlying human being playing that
character now if he was genuine then as
we say in mathematics without loss of
generality we can adapt ourselves to the
circumstance that the actor and the
character were one in the same so if the
actor and the character are one in the
same and that he was in no way a
construct of anyone then no harm no foul
the theory will accommodate that but it
allows us to have a different
possibility that the character and the
actor are two different people another
technique that I like to use is I like
to think about a decision tree and a
decision tree I don't want to have to
say which branch of the decision tree is
true and which branch is false very
often when you share a conspiracy theory
what you find is that people want to
know exactly what do you believe well
what do you think happened what do you
think was really going
well the answer is I don't know but what
if you can come up with a theory that is
true no matter which branch of the
decision tree you're on that you have
confidence in this is where I've been
headed lastly I want to use a technique
which is extremely important to me that
I've talked about before at the behest
of navarre avocado on Twitter so you can
find a Twitter thread that'll will go
under something like the title the
invisible world is first discovered in
the visible worlds failure to close now
what do I mean by that what I mean is is
that sometimes you discover that
something is not right only because the
explanation for everything that can be
seen doesn't add up my favorite example
of this is beta decay in something like
cobalt-60
if you measure the momentum of all of
the visible particles you will notice
that it doesn't add up to a concert a
conserved momentum equation and this is
what allowed Wolfgang Pauli to
hypothesize that there must be something
carrying away some momentum that is
electrically neutral and cannot be seen
and he named it the neutrino the little
neutral one
well something didn't make sense about
Jeffrey Epstein how could somebody have
that much money
claimed to be a hedge fund manager be so
clearly focused on his persona and not
look or sound like anybody I had ever
met in trading at that point I believe
that this person in some sense
represented a failure of the visible
world's failure to close and so I
decided that it was with some
probability not a hundred percent
certainly that this person was in fact a
construct now around I forget when it
was 2005 some point through 2007 Jeffrey
Epstein becomes entangled with Florida
law enforcement for requesting or
arranging massages from underage women
that was almost certainly massage was a
euphemism for some form of child
prostitution this was an extremely
disturbing episode in which he was
vigorous
defended by a high-profile team which is
his right in an adversarial system but
it was with a particular vigor that I
found absolutely disturbing and
unsettling and that the sentence given
to Jeffrey Epstein seemed to be so
reduced compared to what he was being
accused of that I felt like I had to
just check check all of my intuitions
why was such a light sentence being
imposed further people I knew went and
visited him in prison and talked about
him being a friend talked about him
being a massage enthusiast it made no
sense to me that this person who was
being accused of some form of pedophilia
was being treated very differently than
I would have imagined by people that I
very much respected at the time I didn't
understand what was going on but I
started to formulate a second theory and
I haven't heard it discussed much in the
media so I'll share it with you now the
idea is that if you buy the idea that
Jeffrey Epstein was in fact a construct
of the intelligence community my belief
is is that he was constructed to be a
sapiosexual Hugh Hefner in some sense he
was the dan Bilzerian of his day that is
somebody who is not interested in little
girls but is instead interested in young
women women over the age of consent who
by law have every right to associate
with whoever they wish to and can engage
in consensual relations
now you may frown upon it you may look
down upon it you may say that it's an
abuse of power for a man in his 40s 50s
what have you to be cavorting with some
person above the age of consent however
I don't take the same exact view of it
that I take the view of somebody going
below the age of consent so in the era
of me too we have a different situation
in which people are very uncomfortable
even talking about the legal situation
in which women in their early 20s who
may be trying to wield sexual power are
contending with men who may be trying to
wield political or economic power and
that's an issue that I don't have a
particular interest
settling but whatever it is it's very
different than somebody sending people
to a high school to find 15 year old
girls or 14 year old girls for erotic
massages or prostitution or
what-have-you
so my belief was in effect that the
intelligence community that may have
constructed Jeffrey Epstein was
constructing him to be a sapiosexual
Hugh Hefner but that they had stupidly
stupidly and mistakenly hired somebody
who was actually closer to Humbert
Humbert as an actor that is the
underlying actor playing the role of
Jeffrey Epstein Jeffrey Epstein hedge
fund genius was in fact someone with a
pedophilia problem that was probably not
known to the intelligence community when
it constructed the project which I
believe would have had to have dated
from the 80s or 90s when Jeffrey Epstein
first started amassing his network of
high-profile contacts under this
mysterious reputation as a one-of-a-kind
financial genius
as a result that would explain a great
deal of why people's intuition was
wildly off about Jeff people who did not
have a problem with an older rich man
going after young women above the age of
consent were suddenly forced to contend
with the question of was this person
secretly interested in women below the
age of consent and perhaps considerably
below the age of consent so this went
some of the way towards explaining but I
have had another issue that I've tried
to talk to people about which I also
think figures into this story
why was Jeffrey Epstein so focused on
science and in particular why was he
focused on heterodox science keep in
mind I'm just I'm reading I'm reading
nothing this is a completely ad lib so
just allow me to catch my breath in my
theory what I fear and what I believe is
is that the American scientific project
has not understood that it has been
abandoning its scientific assets and if
you look at my work you can notice that
this is a through-line having nothing to
do with Jeffrey Epstein
in effect we have made it impossible for
American scientists to profit using the
market
from their discoveries because we
exclude fundamental discoveries from
intellectual property protection
therefore you have a problem that when
you make a discovery it is both in
excludable if you share it in the
scientific literature and inexhaustible
that is that anyone who discovers it can
use it without precluding anyone else
from discovering from using it ok when
you have something that fits those twin
criterion then even free market
economists will agree that it
constitutes a public good a failure of
the market to keep value and price in
lockstep in essence we pay for
scientific research out of taxpayer
dollars because the market cannot price
it correctly
so you have something which I believe to
be a fantastic value including military
and potentially industrial value as it
is translated from pure science into
technology however for some reason the
United States has been losing its
appetite for funding high-level
scientific research and protecting it
with academic freedom as the university
system goes into freefall that is our
university system is structured as a
Ponzi scheme and after Vannevar bush in
the endless frontier doctrine forced us
to do our blue sky research inside of
universities rather than inside of
research institutions dedicated to the
purpose we developed a weird problem we
would no longer be able to pay our
scientists and use the fact that people
could contribute the labor of their
youth into a system where they would
then become professors to train other
professors if each professor trained
perhaps twenty graduate students to
become professors you can tell that
after a very short period of time you've
got a pyramid scheme that can't keep
expanding as we did be in the post-war
system where we educated sub 10% of our
population at a post-secondary level to
around 1970 or so when we were educating
around 50 percent of our population at a
post-secondary level so when the music
stopped the system started to decay you
had an extremely valuable system I've
said before the theoretical physics
largely constructed our modern economy
he invented the world wide web it
invented the semiconductor
he gave us nuclear power nuclear weapons
our communications technology in the
electromagnetic spectrum so many of the
things that we take for granted
including molecular biology came out of
theoretical physics and so what I have
likened this to is that the United
States had something like a Ferrari
convertible and it left the top down so
that it started getting filled up with
rain and it started scrawling steel me
in mandarin Farsi Russian on its front
bonnet
we are not protecting our scientific
assets in fact when Jeffrey Epstein came
back out of prison I think if I recall
correctly I tweeted that Jeffrey Epstein
was somebody who was funding what the
American government refused to fund and
I recall if I'm not being too self kind
that I said welcome back with a period
rather than an exclamation point because
I was extremely dismayed that we are
fundamentally leaving this open we left
a niche for such a person to start
exploiting us if Jeffrey Epstein was
able to find this niche then I believe
that other nations will be able to find
it as well so what happened inside of
the scientific enterprise is that many
scientists had some memory from inside
of the system when professors would in
fact have potentially second homes or
even third homes where they would be
paid at a level that was commensurate
with finance ears or high-priced lawyers
that in essence the children of academic
families were growing up with the
children of very well-to-do families
because there wasn't such income and
asset inequality in the United States I
believe that they need to pay the
scientific community particularly the
top members of the scientific community
and a far higher level is not a question
of taxpayer dollars it's a question of
first of all being fair to the community
that created our economy those are not
taxpayer dollars they are scientific
dollars in my opinion
we can argue that at some other point
but it's also a question of national
interest that is that is completely
irresponsible for us to pretend that the
market for scientific research talent
should be determined by your ability to
teach undergraduates we should probably
decouple the teaching and research
enterprises we should probably get rid
of the majority of our research
enterprise and we should take care of
the people who are paying power laws at
a very high level for the national
interest it's not a question about pay
overpaying them it's a question of we
are leaving a valuable asset unguarded
and I believe that Jeffrey Epstein was
attempting in part to gain control of
that ass asset that's why people like
George Church or Robert rivers or
Stephen Hawking or any one of a number
of people like Lisa Randall were found
on Jeffery Epstein's Island by the way I
think it's very important to stop using
the fun phrases pedophile Island and
Lolita Express when you have people who
almost certainly are not part of any
kind of orgiastic culture like Lisa
Randall or Betsy Devine it's ridiculous
in part what we're doing is we're
turning a salacious story into a very
dangerous national emergency if in fact
Jeffrey Epstein was up to something very
different than the mainstream story
would have you believe so why is it that
I am so disturbed by this and coming
forward in this way well there are a
number of reasons but one of the reasons
is is that I came to think about the
following issue which I I find
potentially dispositive I've started
asking people who knew Jeffrey Epstein
did the character you met whoever that
person was impress you as being capable
character illogically of taking his own
life out of desperation when he still
clearly had many cards to play he almost
certainly had many secrets involving
very powerful people the man I met was
so confident and so contemptuous of
normal morality that I don't believe he
even bothered particularly by the
reputation of being a pedophile from his
previous stay as a guest of of the state
of Florida I believe the Jeffrey Epstein
in fact was contemptuous he thought it
was ridiculous that he would be jailed
for such a thing and he thought that
while it's a matter of petty morality
for you and me to mull over he simply
had to make sure that he didn't run
afoul of the system again
all right assume that I'm correct that
he was such a person who would laugh at
the shame that others would bestow upon
him then something very interesting
happens as you go down the various
branches of the decision tree you find
that there has to be another unseen
force if this is true is he dead or not
dead well I can put a small weight on
the idea that he isn't even dead
people's deaths have been faked before I
don't think that that's what happened
but it's possible or he could be dead
then he could be dead either by his own
hand or the hand of another if he is
dead by his own hand it could be an
induced suicide as we saw Sullivan was
trying to induce in Martin Luther King
or it could be that his of his own hand
if his own hand could it be out of fear
out of shame or a out of a sense of duty
to something more if he was in fact
murdered a hole would have had had been
punched in the timeline so that somebody
could have gotten to him or there would
have to be a tremendous coincidence that
somehow he was left alone in a jail
which had not had a history of suicides
in over a decade if I recall correctly
in any of these branches of the decision
tree something is at play and something
is at work unless you believe that
somehow I have it wrong and the people
who knew Jeffrey Epstein would support
the idea that he would take his own life
out of fear or shame which I find
essentially impossible given the
character that he chose to project or
that the actor playing the financier and
whiz kid Jeffrey Epstein chose to
protect
project to me I've checked this with
several people and in general everyone
had the same impression that he was
completely contemptuous of normal human
beings with their petty morality it is
by the ability to work over all branches
of the decision tree that I've gained
confidence first that I started talking
about this ages ago
and anybody who I've discussed Jeffrey
Epstein with will remember me using the
word construct even before he was
arrested and jailed for solicitation
prostitution of minors so I've been I've
been at this for 15 years
not knowing it was gonna end like this
I think many of us have tweeted out that
if he was in fact attached to the
intelligence community that he was going
to have to die because otherwise these
secrets would get out and am i scared
that I'm thinking about releasing this
to the general public
yes but I'm also scared about not
releasing this to the general public
my belief is that this was a poorly
constructed operation and that when it
comes to light which intelligence
community it was we're in danger of
countries that I care a great deal about
being thought to have constructed a
pedophilic honey trap using comprar
Monte as the Russian word for that which
would be used to control people in order
to gain some sort of a geopolitical
strategic advantage now I am NOT of the
opinion that Jeffrey Epstein was a
savory character and I'm not saying that
he didn't hire prostitutes or coerce
women into orgies or what-have-you but
my guess is that at the moment he was
not using that the particular kink of
his four children in order to in mesh
scientists or other politicians as the
news media sometimes hints at when it is
not suggesting that he's simply dead by
his own hand
in fact I think it's extremely dangerous
to think about this as being the
decision of a country now I'm not going
to lie I've thought that the country
might be Israel
and as an American Jew who's lived in
Israel
I don't think Israel came to this
decision if in fact he is a product of
the Israeli intelligence network in fact
this would be something that would be
top-secret it would have been decided by
a tiny number of individuals and it is
not right to take down a nation
based upon the idea that you can't even
do intelligence work because you
contrived such a ridiculous idea as
Jeffrey Epstein in order to gain
compromise and therefore control over
influential people inside of another
country
what I would believe is instead that
this is a tiny program and that these
people should come forward or that we
should find them by reinitiating the
church and pike commissions there is now
so much bizarre stuff of this kind that
it is time to revisit the church and
pike commissions of the mid-1970s to
find out what our intelligence and other
intelligence agencies may have been up
to we need something to restore our
confidence and when and if we find out
that a foreign power has been operating
in the u.s. perhaps with our consent or
perhaps we are act in fact gaining some
benefit from an operation that we could
not ourselves do post church in Pike I
think what we would be do well to
realize is is that this situation is not
the responsibility of any country but
the responsibility of people in the
intelligence community who would have
gone out of control now do I know this
to be true absolutely not
am i infallible far from it I wouldn't
have shared with you that I was wrong
about Bernie Madoff
in fact if all of these conspiracy
theories turned out to be exactly true
some of them still remain to be proven
but what I've tried to do is to try to
talk to you about the idea that I don't
think that this story is being fully
explored
I'm extremely dismayed that over a very
brief period of time we went from
suggesting that Jeffrey Epstein was
allegedly dead by his own hand to
believing the medical examiner's report
as if this was conclusive
in fact the charge that he might have
been murdered with an understanding of
the powers that be that controlled the
correctional facility in which he was
housed includes the charge that the
medical examiner's report would likely
have been doctored that's not an
additional charge you wouldn't murder
somebody if the report would
conclusively show murder unless you
actually knew that you had enough
control over the system to control at
all furthermore there has to be a
facility that keeps local law
enforcement local medical officers from
stumbling over something of high value
you couldn't responsibly run the
intelligence community which has to be
able to carry out covert operations
operations that are disturbing
operations that are effective without
constantly fearing that low-level law
enforcement and low-level medical
examiners could blow the whole thing sky
high now whatever the facility is that
keeps our high-level intelligence work
safe from low-level enforcement could
easily been operative I don't mean to
suggest that it was only that it is not
reasonable to suggest that it is crazy
to assume that the medical examiner
could be induced to file a report to
support a fish Almera t'v it is time to
return to investigative journalism we
can trust it is time to return to
committees of the House and Senate that
have the power to investigate these
things and it is long past due that the
intelligence services be revisited if
they in fact have very little to hide
then this shouldn't really be a big
problem but at the moment the American
people have lost full confidence in our
ability to get to the bottom of truths
as to whether foreign countries are
meddling in our national elections as to
whether foreign countries are using
their ability to send graduate students
into the stem pipeline to spy on us as
to whether foreign countries are using
our tech platforms in order to help them
with their military advantage over the
United States now I really don't want to
come back to the Jeffrey Epstein story
so what
I'm saying to you is it's quite possible
that Jeffrey Epstein is simply dead by
his own hand that he was a pervy
billionaire or near billionaire who had
an interest in science and also an
interest in young women that ranged from
women at prep of age 23 down either to
18 15 12 what have you
maybe the official story is true all I'm
trying to suggest is is that for some
reason I picked this one person to tell
a fifteen-year story about that I
believed he was an intelligence
construct of probably another country
operating in the center of the United
States elite and I believe that that is
an additional piece of information
because there's no one else that I've
been telling the story about I've never
met another person like this this is a
completely soui generous exception to my
general understanding of the world and I
think if I am correct that there was
something very much amiss that it was
obviously amiss obvious to anybody who
wished to see it just as the world
clearly closed their eyes to Geoffrey
Epstein's problems when it was found
that he was asking for massages from
underage girls in Florida
somebody was turning a blind eye towards
the story almost certainly because it
was too salacious not to be interesting
it's the kind of a story that would move
newspapers it would sell advertising
spots
it's far too juicy for people to take
this little of an interest in and I want
to say one last thing about this Jeffrey
Epstein was in meshed with a guy named
Jon Brockman who was a guy who in some
sense gave me my first break on a larger
stage it is commonly believed at the
moment by certain members of the media
that Jon Brockman was complicit in the
underage behavior underage interest that
Jeff Epstein showed in young girls the
one thing I can add is is that I met Jon
Brockman and his wife katenka
Matson at Stewart brands interval bar
sometime in the last
I don't know one two three years and
when John and I sat down I can tell you
with certainty that John warned me that
he had had an interaction with Jeffrey
that he had found very disturbing and
that John had been forced to walk out of
his house realizing that Jeffrey Epstein
had had a problem now John has not come
forward and I don't know that there's
anybody else in a position to tell this
story but I can say with some certainty
that John was not happy about this and
that if John was in fact tolerant of a
Hugh Hefner style person the person I
met for no no reason to say this to me
was certainly not okay with Jeffrey
Epstein was in fact warning me away from
him
and I had no interest in in seeing
Jeffrey at that point so I do wish to
say that I think that the conspiracy
theorizing that I'm seeing is of a lower
quality and a lower level of course if
you want I could find out that the
entire edge network is somehow at risk
and implicated but I can say is somebody
on the very periphery I wrote no books
for John I didn't go to the billionaires
dinners I never went to this island I
never flew in the plane I met him once
and I had a phone call with him
afterwards I can tell you that I don't
personally believe that John brockman
was caught up in this at the level that
is now being alleged by certain members
of the press who I feel are perhaps not
as responsible as they might be
anyway that's more or less what I have
to say on the subject and with this I
intend to to the extent possible exit
the Jeffrey Epstein conspiracy business
you've been through the portal thanks
for joining us
[Music]